那么多年来……
All these years.
我用稀奇古怪的题材 写过那么多古怪的小说
I've written so many books with fantastic themes.
每一个人碰到都问我
Everyone that sees me will ask.
他说，你怎么想像出来的呢？
how can you come out all these?
还是真的经历呢？
Is it real story?
问这个问题 其实是一个很傻的一个问题
This is a stupid question
因为每一个人每一天
Everyone, in everyday.
在你身边发生那么多的事情
there are a lot happen around you.
每一件小事情
Every tiny little thing.
只要你肯去深入发掘的话
if you wish you dig up.
都可以变成一个稀奇古怪的故事
it may come out with a fantastic story
尤其如果你经常跟朋友喝酒聊天的话
If you hang out with your friends.
在每一个人的身上都可以有很多
you may find out many interesting stories
曲折离奇的故事给你发掘出来
thru their talk.
好像今天晚上这样的情形 有两个朋友已经到了
Tonight, for instance. two of my friends are here.
卫斯理
Wesley
倪先生
Mr, Ngai
你好，原振侠呢？
Hello, where's Yuan Chen?
他在那边
He's over there.
你的眼镜好漂亮呀
You've got nice glasses
倪先生
Mr, Ngai
恭喜几位当选亚洲小姐
Congratulations on winning the titles of Miss Asia.
谢谢……      干杯……
Thanks Cheers.
原振侠，你前一阵子不是跟卫斯理
Yuan Chen, you had a daring adventure
有一件很惊险的事情吗？
with Wesley, didn't you?
是吗？说来听听
Really? Tell us about it
倪先生才是最会讲故事的人
Mr, Ngai is a good story teller.
应该由倪先生讲才对
Let him tell it
一个好的故事，从一杯好的酒开始
A good story, starts from a good glass of wine.
猎狗呼叫雷鸟……
Hound calling Thunderbird
各单位准备好了没有……？
Are all units ready?
我是雷鸟，里面有六个劫匪
I'm Thunderbird There are 6 bandits.
其中一个是神枪手
One of them is a sharpshooter
他们每个人都有重型武器
They all carry heavy weapons.
吩咐大家小心点
Tell everyone to be alert.
猎狗，你怎么啦？
What's up there, Hound?
猎狗，你怎么啦？猎狗
Hound, how are you, Hound?
快点停火
Stop fire!
下面的人听着
You all listen.
你们开枪打伤了一个人质
you gunned down a hostage!
现在他的心脏病很严重
He's having a serious heart attack.
如果你们的医生还不来，他就死定了
If the doctor doesn't come, he'll be dead!
医生很快就来
The doctor is on his way
我们已经包围了你们
You have been surrounded
你们没有机会逃走了，快点投降吧
You stand no chance of escape, Give up!
什么事？
What is it?
小姐
Miss.
我是西方日报记者
I'm the reporter of Western Daily.
我们知道，不过里面很危险 你不能进去，请你走吧
We know But it's dangerous so you can't get in
麻烦你呀，我只是进去拍张照 不行，都说不行啦……
Please, I just wanna take a picture. No way!
怎么啦？神奇女侠
What now, Wonder Woman?
他们不让我进去
They don't let me in
我是原医生，你是何Sir吧？
I'm Doctor Yuan Are you Captain Ho?
人质在里面，他向来都有心脏病
The hostage is inside, He has heart attack
为什么一定要找我？    是这样的
Why have to be me? Well.
我们知道原医生 有过很多冒险的事迹
We have heard
胆识过人
a lot your bravery
我们希望你进去放一个蓝光弹
We hope you can go in to plant a bomb
跟我们里应外合救人质
to help us save the hostage
我不熟
I don't know what to do.
江帮办
Inspector Kong
Yes，Sir
Yes, sir.
原医生，等一会儿 由我假扮护士跟你进去
Dr,Yuan, I'll be the nurse to follow you in.
让我来引爆
I'll defuse it
你去准备     是
Go and prepare everything Yes!
这个药箱下面有暗格 蓝光弹就在里面
The bomb is in a layer of the first aid kit.
怎么样？OK了吧？
How is everything? OK?
原医生，你记住，是十二点整
Dr, Yuan, remember, it's 1 2 o'clock sharp.
到时候我们会冲进去的
We'll break in at that time
医生进来了，不要开火
The doctor's here, Don't open fire
散开
Scatter!
不许动     八婆，别动呀
Freeze! Bitch, don't move
我也是女人来的，走呀
I'm a woman, bitch.
走呀
Go!
小子，别耍花样呀
Don't play tricks, kid
病人呢？
Where's the patient?
起来，走呀，走
Get up, go!
把听筒给我
Gimme the stethoscope
大家不用怕，我是医生来的
Calm down, I'm a doctor
强心针
The heart-stimulant injection
你怎么啦？
What are you doing?
大哥，有枪
Brother, a gun!
臭小子，你敢耍我？
Bloody kid, you dare to fool me?
Start
Start!
站住
Stop!
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是个记者
I'm a reporter
你知不知道你刚才这么做会害死人的？
Don't you know that you nearly ruined us?
对不起
I'm sorry
我的相机呢？我想拍几张照片
Where's my camer? I wanna take some pictures.
你还要拍？
You still wanna take pictures?
原医生，谢谢你
Thank you, Dr, Yuan
现场已经被我们控制了
We are now in control.
那好吧，我先走了   OK，收队
Good, I gotta go now. OK, retreat
是
Yes!
你是不是想抓我？
Are you gonna arrest me?
漂亮的女孩子我见过很多了
I've seen many pretty girls.
像你这么疯疯癫癫的我真的没见过
None is crazy like you
你知不知道你这么做会坐几年牢？
Don't you know that you may get in jail?
那……        你还不快点走？
That Go now
谢谢你
Thank you
原医生，谢谢你
Dr, Yuan, thank you
小意思
Not a problem.
何Sir
Captain Ho.
刚才幸亏江帮办英勇，谢谢你
We have to thank lnspector Kong for just now
何Sir
Captain Ho!
你不是那位专写性学的楚博士吗？ 丹尼王呀
Ain't you that sexology writer Dr, Chor? Danny Wong?
听说你近来在写一篇论文……
I've heard that you have been writing an essay
就是说气候对中国男人 性能力的关系是不是？
on the climate's effect on male sex potential?
这只不过是数学上的比例问题
This is merely a ratio in Mathematics.
温度跟时间是成正比例的
The temperature and time constitute a ratio.
南方的温度高一点，大概是一个钟头
The length is one hour in tropical South
中部就是半个钟头
Half an hour in the central part
北方的温度低一点，大概是两三分钟
About 2-3 minutes in the low-temperature North.
我记得你是海南岛的
I remember you come from the South Sea lsland.
是呀，照你这么推论
According to your theory.
我是北极人了
I should have come from North Pole.
不会吧？
Really?
那边几个小妞可真漂亮呀
There are some pretty chicks there
楚博士，美酒是你的
Dr, Chor, take the wine.
美女该是我的了吧？
Leave me the girl.
好不好笑？傻  好笑，好笑……
Is it fun? It's funny
你们信不信星座的？
Do you believe in constellation?
我一看你的样子就是处女座的
I can readily see you must be a Virgo.
好，你慢慢解释吧 安妮，我们到那边坐
Well, take your time. Annie, let's sit over there
你知不知道处女座的女孩 最好找个金牛座的男孩
A Virgo girl's best mate is a Taurus guy.
好像我一样，你一定是巨蟹座
just like me You must be Cancer.
我家里有很多收藏品的
I have quite a lotta collections.
有一个新几内亚猎头族制成的人头
A human head made by the New Guinea tribe.
缩得像猴子头那么大
It was shrunk to the size of a monkey head
这么恐怖呀
It sounds horrible
还有呀，有几只传说 是外星人砍下来的脚趾
And, there are some toes chopped down by alien
还是这么恶心呀，还有些什么？
so nasty, what else?
还有我罗，原振侠
And me, Yuan Chan.
我有很重要的事要跟你说
I have something important to talk to you
你搞什么鬼？
What the heck are you doing?
小姐，在你还没有被他骗到手之前
Miss, don't be fooled by him.
我老实跟你说吧，他已经结了婚啦
Lemme be honest to you, he's married.
你说什么呀？
What are you talking about?
我看，我还是先走开一会儿
Please excuse me a while.
拜拜      安妮……
Bye. Annie!
你先不要走呀
You stay.
你现在究竟想怎么样？
What on earth do you exactly want?
对不起呀，我也知道 破坏了你的泡妞计划
Sorry, I know I have screwed up your plan
不过我有重要事找你
But I need you on something important.
你说吧
Shoot!
好，我代表西方日报想跟你做个专访
I'd like to feature you in Western Daily
我想介绍一下你的英雄事迹
to introduce your heroic deeds.
给你拍一辑裸照
I'll take a naked photo of you
我保证拍得很有美感
I promise you that it will have a sense of beauty
我的摄影技术不差的，请你相信我
My technique is not bad, Trust me
对不起，那位先生，不关我的事……
Sorry, it's not my fault It's that guy,,.
傻瓜
Idiot!
停车    不要再见了
Stop! Sayonara!
嗨
Hi.
傻瓜，我还以为追不上你呢？
Idiot, I thought I couldn't catcha
你这个人真是下流 卑鄙无耻，你是个臭男人
You such a bloody nasty bastard!
对不起
I'm sorry
你吓了我一跳
You really hurt me
你怎么进来的？玛莉亚哪儿去了？
How did you get in? Where's Maria?
我给了她一千块钱 还跟她说你放她一天假
I gave her $1 000 and said you let her have a day off.
我明白了
Oh, I see
今晚真是给女人玩惨了
I've fooled by woman all night.
原振侠
Yuan Chan!
你是谁？
Who are you?
你要跟我回泰国
You have to follow me back to Thailand
你要救自己，还要救芭珠
You have to help yourself and Betsy
你说什么？
What are you talking about?
你身上的血降已经满一年了
Your blood spell has reached one year
很快就会发作
You will soon relapse
芭珠也中了鬼面降
Betsy got a ghost spell as well
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
我真的不明白你说什么？
I don't understand what you are talking about
你不要装蒜，这是我在泰国的位址
Stop acting, This is my address in Thailand.
我等你三天
I'll wait for you three days
先别走
Don't go away
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
我叫黑龙
My name is Black Dragon
听着，千万不要近女色
Listen, keep away from sex
否则即刻会发作
Or you may have a quick relapse
那个人是谁？怎么那么凶？
Who's that guy? I'm so scared
没事，不用怕
That's alright, No problem.
卫先生，你是我最好的朋友 又是我师父
Mr, Wai, you're my best friend and master
我想只有你才能帮我
I think only you can help me.
你去过泰国北部吗？
Have you ever been to North Thailand?
阿素，麻烦你冲两杯咖啡给我们
So, bring us two cups of coffee, please.
好啊
Sure.
你似乎中了巫术之中最厉害的血咒
Apparently you have been under blood spell.
我想知道详细情形
Lemme know the detail.
事情是这样的
It was like this
在一年前
About a year ago.
我和一队医学探险队到泰国北部
I followed a medical team to North Thailand.
去找一种医治爱滋病的草药
to seek a kind of herbs for treating AlDS
早    早
Morning. Morning.
早
Good morning.
教授，我想到湖的那边走一走
Professor, I'd like to take a walk about the lake.
你要小心点，这儿接近 中国云南的苗族
Be careful Here's quite near to Yunnan, Chinese Miao tribe.
中泰边境的地方 听说有一个蛊族，特别精于巫术
They say a kind of worm tribe specialize in witchcraft
巫术我就不相信 我只相信有外星人存在
I only believe in science.
对不起，我打破了你的宝物
Sorry for breaking your gem
不要紧，我还有好多，送给你好了
Never mind I still have spare, Keep this.
真的？    真的
Really? Yes
我要走了
I have to go.
你不应该接近那个女孩子的
You should get close to that girl.
蛊族的人残忍冷酷
Their tribe's cruel
而且还有很多不可思议的邪术
and knows witchcraft
教授，跟她聊两句就下降头
Professor, if they cast a spell to anyone who talks to.
那他们那帮人不是很忙？
they must be damn busy
总之我是队长
Anyways, I'm the team leader
我对于你们这班人的安全是有责任的
It's my responsibility to protect you guys.
这些鼓声？
Sounds of the drum?
这些是蛊族的鼓声来的，是祭神鼓
It comes from the worm tribe and signal offerings
那他们是不是在祭神？
They are offering to god, eh?
你们千万不要过看呀
Don't ever go and see it.
我们不会过去看的……
We won't!
好大的场面
What a big procession!
过去
Go over there.
是她
It's her
你说是哪个她呀？
Who?
就是我下午看见的那个
The girl I saw this afternoon
是谁呀？到底是谁呀？ 我也不知道
Which one? I don't know either
你决定了没有？
Have you made up your mind?
我不会答应你的
I won't say YES.
你可能会被选中祭神的
Probably you have been chosen for offering
等老祖宗醒过来的时候，你就要死了
When Old Ancestor wakes up, you'll die
你故意调开黑龙再来选我 我不会屈服的
You deliberately sent Black Dragon away and picked me
我爱，就只爱黑龙一个人
I only love him.
我不会答应你的
I won't submit.
我的子民
My guys.
一年一度老祖宗醒过来的时候
As a previous years. when Old Ancestor wakes up.
神的旨意会选择 哪一个会得到的神的荣誉
someone honored by God will be chosen.
大巫师，芭珠是前任族长的女儿
Betsy is the daughter of the ex-chief.
请不要把她祭神
please don't offer her to God
这些是神的旨意
This is the will of God.
但是我们从来没有试过
But we have never tried
还有谁不服的？
Anyone else refusing to do this?
送进古墓
Send them to the grave.
我去救她
I have to rescue her
不是吧？
You kidding?
你发神经呀？很容易没命的？
Are you crazy? You may be killed!
我会随机应变的，你们去拿武器来吧
I'll play to the score. You guys go get the weapon
不要呀……        别去呀
No Don't go
怎么办？     现在怎么办？
What now? What shall we do now?
你快点走吧
Run!
他是我们的老祖宗，他不会死的
He's our Old Ancestor. He won't die.
你快点走吧，你不要管我了
Run! Leave me!
都叫你快点走，不要管我啦
I told you to run Just leave me!
救我呀……
Help me!
快点
Hurry up!
有人破坏祭坛，你们快去看看
Intruders! Go and see!
是
Yes!
又有鼓声
Drum sound?
他知道有人破坏祭神，要追杀你们
He's pursuing you for your intrusion
走
Run!
教授
Professor!
你不听命令，你看现在弄成这个样子
You brought the mess because you didn't listen to me
快回营地收拾东西走
Go back to the camp and pack up at once.
走，快点走
Go, quickly.
芭珠，芭珠……
Besty, Besty!
上车
Get in the car!
你们两个破坏祭神，亵渎了老祖宗
You two destroyed the sacrifice and blasphemed Old Ancestor
我今天要代表神，给你们应得的惩罚
I'll punish you behalf of God
教授，你……
Professor, you...
原振侠，救我
Yuan Chan, help me!
这些虫子繁殖得很快
These worms are highly prolific
不过你放心
Don't worry.
我不会用这些来对付你的
I won't use them on you
我对不起你们
I'm sorry for you guys
你快点走
Run, quickly!
不要让他们抓住你，你走……
Don't let them get hold of you Run!
这个是我的护身降来的
This is my talismanic worm.
我现在用来救你，但是……
I'm using it to help you, but
当我醒过来之后，芭珠已经走了
When I woke up, Betsy was gone.
我身上的七个血印也全都没有了
The 7 bloodstains on my body were gone.
所以我一个人走了
So I left alone.
我回到香港已经一年了 什么事也没有
I've been back to HK a year and nothing happened
想不到现在……
But now,,.
黑龙警告过你，为什么你不相信他？
Black Dragon warned you Why don't you trust him?
我都不认识这个人 谁知道他找我想干什么？
I don't even know him How do I know what he wants me?
说得也对
That's right
你们还……
You guys
怎么了？振侠
What's wrong, Chan?
阿素，去把药箱拿来
So, go get the first aid kit.
第二个血咒爆开了
The 2nd blood curst has burst
那第一个在什么时候爆的？
When did the first burst occur?
跟现在的时间差不多
More or less the same time.
如果真的这样 那就是二十四小时爆一个
It means one burst every 24 hour.
五天之内就会爆到心脏，你就会死了
When it spreads to the heart. you'll die in 5 days
卫先生，你对巫术的认识这么深
Mr. Wai, you know witchcraft well.
我有没有得救？
Is there any chance of survival for me?
血咒是巫术之中最神秘和最复杂的
Blood curse is the most mysterious.
也是最厉害的一种
and complex of its kind in witchcraft.
芭珠虽然用护身降保护过你
Betsy used a spell to save you
但只能保护你一年
But it worked for one year only
所以黑龙叫你去泰国一定有理由
There must be a reason Black Dragon wants you go to go Thailand.
你的意思是叫我去泰国
You want me to go to Thailand?
振侠，解铃还须系铃人
Chan,only the doer can undo a damage done.
好，我明天一早去找黑龙
Ok, I'll go see him tomorrow
这么刺激的事情 你一定要给我独家资料呀
Such an exciting thing. You gotta gimme the scoop on this
又是你？
You again?
表哥，你跟他很熟的吗？
Cousin, you know much about him?
卫先生
Mr. Wai?
振侠，彩虹是卫先生的表妹 一向都很任性的
Chan, Rainbow is Wai's spoiled cousin
你不要怪她
Don't be mad
我发觉什么都有你的份
You wanna screw up everything
我跟他很熟的
I know him well
这样好了，我不用你替我拍裸照了
Fine, I don't wanna take your naked photo
你让我跟你去泰国
Lemme go with you to Thailand, OK?
你以为我去玩？
You think I'm going traveling?
彩虹，这件事情非常严重 你不可以去
Rainbow, it's serious, You can't go.
这么说你是看不起我了？
You mean I'm not qualified?
你知不知道 我跟原医生一起出生入死过的
I went through fire and water with Dr Yuan.
原医生你说是不是？
You agree so?
我不会让你跟我一起去的
I won't let you go with me.
振侠，明天我有点事情要办
Chan, I have something to do tomorrow.
后天我赶去帮你
I'll meet you up the day after.
你有什么事打电话给泰国警方
Call the Thai police if anything happens.
我会跟他们联络的
I'll keep in touch with them.
谢谢你
Thank you
别客气
No problem
表哥，你都不帮我的？
Cousin, you don't wanna help me?
记者搜集资料要有个限度
A reporter shouldn't go too far in coverage.
这件事有生命危险的
This is a matter of life and death.
你只是贪玩，我不想你出什么事
You are only in for kicks, Stay out of it.
原振侠先生吗？
Mr. Yuan Chan?
我是
I am.
请你跟我来
Please follow me.
你是……？
You are?
我老板叫我来接你的 你去了就明白了
My boss sends me to pick you up You'll know when you see
你老板呢？
Where's your boss?
原先生，请你先坐一会儿
Mr, Yuan, please take a rest
谢谢
Thanks
傻瓜
Idiot
又是你？
You again?
我比你早一班飞机来的
I came on earlier flight
怎么有这么多武器在这儿？
Why there are so many weapons?
我们要进原始森林去冒险呀
We're going to a primitive jungle
不带这些东西怎么够安全呢
It's unsafe without them.
还有这把是最新的镭射导向枪
This is the latest laser-guided gun.
你买得起吗？
Can you afford it?
我爸是董太平呀
My dad is Tung Tai Ping.
香港地产大王董太平？
Property magnate Tung Tai Ping?
我管他什么王
I couldn't care less
总之他有一张没有限额 的金卡给我用就行了
As long as I have a Gold card for an unlimited sum
漂亮，无知，年轻，不知死活
Pretty, nescience, young, hell-bent,,.
再加上有钱
and rich.
我想你是全世界最麻烦的女人了
I think you are the most troublesome woman in the world
我每次找资料都是自己掏腰包的
I always pay for into out of my own pocket
我们现在不是去打仗
We are not going to war
同时巫术也不是这些东西 可以打得死的，小姐
These can't overcome witchcraft.
我们来谈谈生意吧？
Let's talk about business
我已经在老总面前夸下了海口
I've already made a promise to the editor
又跟合众社联络过了
And got in touch with the United Press
如果能拿到你的资料就全世界登头条
If your info can be front-page in world newspaper.
利益你占一半吧？
I'll split half the profit with you
我没空跟你一起疯
I'm in no mood for your frenzied idea
我可不管那么多，总之我一定要去的
I don't care, I wanna go with you.
难道你能绑得住我吗？
Are you going to tie me up?
喂，死傻瓜，你放了……
Hey, idiot, let me go.
不要低估男人呀
Don't ever underrate a man
你终于来了
You finally come
你似乎……？
You seem like
我一回来就被人追杀
I was being pursued immediately returned.
谁追杀你？
Who pursued you?
是大巫师，他知道我找过你
The sorcerer, He knew that I found you.
于是勾结曼谷的黑社会 联手来对付我们
He conspired with the underworld against us.
原来他们是有联络的
They're all of a kind
所以我一回来就被人伏击
I was assaulted when I returned.
那我们即刻走
Let's leave right now.
这里就是蛊族？
Is this the worm tribe?
不是，这个是善良的部族 以耕种为生
No, it's a good tribe working of farmers.
但是蛊族经常骚扰他们
But they often attacked by the worm tribe.
黑龙，你回来就好了
Dragon, it's good to have you back
族长，发生了什么事情？
Chief, what happened?
我们这儿发生了一件怪事
A weird thing happened.
今天下午村子里所有的小孩子 突然全都不见了
All kids in the village disappeared this afternoon.
突然不见了？      是呀
All disappear? Yep
什么事？
What happened?
我们村里的孩子突然神秘失踪了
All kids in our village are disappeared.
一定是被大巫师抓去炼鬼仔降
It must be the sorcerer have abducted them for casting Little Ghost Spell
鬼仔降？
Little Ghost Spell?
鬼仔降要用一百个孩子的血 才能够炼成
Yes, it's made of 1 00 children's blood
他们会飞行、吸血，挡者必死
They can fly, suck blood and kill people
可是三年之后就不能再用了
The spell has to be remade
一定要重新再炼
after three years.
他真是太残忍了
How cruel he is!
是呀，我在祭神的那天晚上 也见过那个小鬼
Right, I saw the little ghost on the offering night.
族长希望我带全村的勇士 把孩子们救回来
The chief wants me to bring men to rescue the kids
好
OK.
我也要去呀
I wanna go, too.
今晚好安静呀！      是呀
It's so quiet tonight. Yep
静得连虫声也没有，一定有问题
Not even chirps There must be something wrong.
小心点
Be careful!
快点走呀
Run quickly!
你们不要走，别乱跑，回来
Don't run Come back!
好痛呀
It hurts!
我早叫你别跟着来 你知不知道这里多危险？
I told you not to follow. Don't you know how dangerous is it?
不跟着来也已经跟了
I've already followed you all the way
不跟下去那个不就是白痴
There's no way not to continue.
你知不知道？这里埋了很多机关的
Don't you know that there are many booby-traps here?
你放心好了，我在美国念书的时候
Don't worry, I have read quite many books of Vietcong tactics
看过很多有关越战杀人机关的书
when I studied in US
这样就可以证明 我可以自己照顾自己了吧
That shows I can take care of myself.
不要说了，我们要争取时间，走吧
Fine, we have to work against time now, Let's go.
我上去看看，你们别吵呀
I'll go up and have a look, Keep quiet
彩虹
Rainbow!
你去哪儿？
Where are you going?
去照相呀
To take pictures
彩虹，你跟着我 我就要向卫先生负责你的安全
Rainbow, I have to be responsible for your safety if you're with me
这儿太危险，我不可以让你乱来的
It's too dangerous I can't let you go
用不着你负责，大男人
I don't care, What a male chauvinist!
彩虹，你听我说好不好？
Rainbow, listen.
这儿的事我经历过，实在太危险了
I've been through this It's too dangerous
有些事你想也想不到的
Things are beyond your control.
放手呀
Let go!
我警告你，你要再碰我一下
I'm telling you, if you touch me again.
我就告诉我表哥，说你非礼我
I'll tell my cousin you hares me
不过以你的声誉来说
Though with your reputation.
起码十个人之中也有 两个人是不相信的
few people will believe that.
我不管你说什么？总之你要听我的
I don't care what you say You have to listen to me
不然我就脱掉你的裤子 打你屁股，然后拍照
Or I'll spank you without pants
你敢？
How dare you?
你好卑鄙
You nasty!
卑鄙又怎么样？
So what?
我懒得理你，我走了 我再也不回来了
I won't care about you I'm leaving now, I won't come back.
好，随便你
Up to you
就算我回头的时候 被毒蛇咬了，被毒箭射了
I won't return even if I were bitten by snakes.
被毒男人吓着了，我也不回来了
hit by arrows or scared by men!
我懒得理你了，我看你后不后悔？
I won't care for you anymore Don't regret.
你好狠心
You're so cruel hearted
拜拜了
Bye-bye
怎么走得这么快？
She's away in a twinkle
那些小孩子都关在笼子里 有很多人看守
The kids are all caged and guarded.
我看不如先救芭珠吧？
We'd better go and help Betsy first.
好
OK.
彩虹姑娘呢？
Where's Miss Rainbow?
她又发小姐脾气，已经回去了
She got pissed off and she left
别管她，对了，芭珠姑娘呢？
Never mind her Where's Betsy?
芭珠
Betsy?
黑龙
Dragon.
我把原医生带来了
I've brought back Dr Yuan.
我来了，芭珠
I'm here, Betsy
你们不要过来
Don't come over
我不想任何人看见我现在的样子
I don't want anyone to see me now.
算了，我看过她的样子 被她吓了一跳
Forget it, Her looks scared me
芭珠，我身上的第四颗血咒 已经爆开了
Betsy, the 4th blood curse on me has burst.
现在要想办法救你和我
We have to figure out how to save you and me
我爸爸临死之前曾经告诉我
My dad told me before he died.
有种神奇的圣物叫舍利子 可以解一切的降头
Some holy ashes can break any kinds of spell
一年前，我中了鬼面降之后 就翻查过祖宗的典籍
I consulted the records of the tribe.
终于知道舍利子收藏的地方
And have found the hiding place.
在哪里？
Where?
藏在山洞的大佛，无路可上
A large Buddha in a cave It's out of reach.
根本就没有人爬上去过
No one can climp up.
所以就拿不到舍利子
So they are unobtainable
我相信你是上天派来给我的救星
I believe that you're my saviour from Heaven.
所以我叫黑龙来找你
So I sent Dragon to get you
可以试试
We can have a try
你还有三天的寿命 你不想试也要试了
You only have 3 days to live. No other choice
我回去给他们打电报
I'll go telegram them.
叫人带齐装备来
Askk them to prepare everything.
还有，原医生，舍利子拿了出来之后
Besides, the Ashes will wither in 6 hours
六小时就会枯了
after you take out.
救命呀，你们干什么？快点放我下来
Help! What are you doing? Put me down!
最多我给钱你们，快放了我
I'll give you money, Release me!
快放了我
Release me!
放开她
Release her.
你一定是这里的大老板 你真是个大好人
You must be the boss here. You're such a nice guy.
我先走了，拜拜
I gotta go, bye
其实我只是走错了路 不小心掉在陷阱里了嘛
I've got the wrong way and been trapped
是不是黑龙带你来的？
Did you send by Black Dragon?
不是呀，我是来采集标本的
No, I'm here to collect specimens
你这么英明神武，我替你拍张照
You look handsome. Lemem take a photo for you
去死吧
Damn you!
行了，我知道了，就这样吧，OVER
OK, I know Fine Over!
装备和救星就快到了
Backup and equipment are coming soon
彩虹还没有回来？
Rainbow's not back yet.
奇怪，这么久还不见她回来？
What takes her so long?
究竟到哪儿去了？
Where 's she been to?
有两个可能，一个是死了 一个就是让他们抓去了
There're 2 possibilities, one is dead. and one is been caught
如果被人抓去了，会关在哪儿呢？
If she's been caught, where could she be?
她是外人，一定会送到大巫师那儿
She's an outsider. must be taken to the sorcerer.
那我们先去救芭珠
Let's save Betsy first.
先去救彩虹
Rescue Rainbow.
好朋友
Good buddy!
彩虹姑娘
Miss Rainbow.
彩虹她没什么事吧？
How is her?
她的体温很奇怪 可是又没有发烧和发冷的迹象
Her temperature is weird But she's not having a fever or cold
我出去看看救兵到了没有？
Lemme go and see if the backup's arrived
彩虹
Rainbow!
什么事？
What happened?
她失去了常性，还力大无穷
She goes berserk and is herculean
彩虹……你怎么啦？
Rainbow, what are you doing?
抓住她
Catch her!
怎么会搞成这样呢？
What happened?
她被大巫师抓去了
She's caught by the Sorcerer.
我们救她回来的时候已经是这样了
Then she's like this after we found her.
依我看，她是中了黑心降 所以力大无穷
I think she must have got the Black Spell.
见人就杀
So she's herculean and wants to kill
那么我们怎么替她解降呢？
How can we break the spell?
让我来
Lemme help you.
芭珠？
Betsy?
要解黑心降就要以黑制黑
Black is needed to break a black spell.
用七种黑色动物的血 包括黑羊，黑牛
Mix the blood of Black sheep, oxen.
黑狗，黑猫，黑蛇，黑鹰和黑蜥蜴
dogs, cats, snakes, eagles and lizards.
将七种血混和煮热，让她浸泡
Boil it and bathe her with it.
泡到她醒过来为止
Immerse her until she wakes up
鬼呀
Ghost!
怎么了？       什么事？
What happened? What's up?
她看见我的脸
She saw my face
没事，没事
It's OK.
她是被大巫师害成这个样子的
The sorcerer persecuted her like this
全靠她救回你的命
She saved you.
她已经没事了
She's fine now
原医生，时间不多了 你快点去拿舍利子吧
Dr, Yuan, there's not much time. Go find the Ashes?
黑龙
Black Dragon
无论你拿不拿到舍利子 你一定要回来
No matter if you can find it. you have to come back
我要跟你一起去
I wanna go with you
彩虹，不要任性
Rainbow, be good
那……你一定要回来呀
Then,,,you have to come back!
什么事？
What happened?
卫先生，我肋骨上第六个血咒爆开了
Mr. Wai, the 6th curse has burst.
但是流血不多
Not much bleeding.
可是当第七个血咒爆的时候
But when the 7th bursts.
你全身的血就会从血洞流出来
all your blood will spill out.
卫先生，明天就是我在世上最后一天
Mr, Wai, tomorrow is the last day of my life
振侠，我不相信命运 可以控制一个勇敢的人
Yuan Chan, I don't believe in fate can contral a brave man.
我相信人定胜天
I think man conquers fate.
黑龙
Black Dragon.
大巫师叫什么名字？
what's the name of that sorcerer?
阿古拉大巫师
Sorcerer Aquala
阿古拉？
Aquala?
阿古拉家族的巫术是 中南半岛之中最神秘和最残忍的
The witchcraft of this clan is the most mysterious and cruel in the South.
他有没有炼鬼仔降
Did he practice Little Ghost Spell?
有
Yes
你们马上找只母牛，要大肚子的
Get a pregnant cow at once
宰了之后把胎盘留下，还有……
Slaughter it and get her placenta out.
杀一条黑狗，把血留下，去吧
A black dog as well and get its blood.
是
Yes!
卫斯理，用来干什么？
Wesley, what is it for?
以前我跟阿古拉家族中 其中一个儿子做过朋友
To break the Little Ghost Spell.
他教过我怎么破“鬼仔降”的方法
a friend of Aquala Clan taught me that
我不知道有没有效
I don't know if it works
振侠，这一次要靠你自己了
Chan, it's all up to yourself.
老祖宗……赐给我力量
Old Ancestor, gimme power!
用血的力量，集中变成血鬼
Use the blood power to turn into blood ghosts
快去给我把原振侠他们杀了
Go kill the guys of Yuan Chan!
那两颗舍利子呢？
Where are those two grains of ashes?
在它那对眼睛里
Inside the eyes
我们要慢慢地爬上去，你没问题吧？
We gotta climb up. do you have problem with it?
喜玛拉雅山我都爬过了
Ha, I have even climbed the Himalaya.
传说上去拿舍利子的人 没有一个可以走出去的
They say no one trying it has ever come out.
要看我们的了
It all depends on us
当心
Watch out!
小心
Be careful!
原振侠……
Yuan Chan!
各位大师
Masters.
我们拿舍利子是用来降魔救人
we try to get them to help someone only.
请各位大师成全我们
Please do us a favor, masters.
快走
Run, quick!
闪开
Duck it!
原振侠……
Yuan Chan!
快吞下舍利子，先解除你的血降
Swallow it now to break the blood spell.
快吞了它
Swallow it!
我们要在两小时内赶回去
We have to go back in 2 hours.
要不然另外一颗舍利子就没用了
Or the other grain will become ineffective
彩虹跟芭珠被人抓去了 你们快救她们，快点去
Rainbow Betsy have been taken by them. Go rescue them quickly!
迟点跟你们会合，走
I'll catcha you guys later.
老祖宗今天一定很高兴
Old Ancestor is so happy today.
有三男三女送来给他吃
To have three men and three girls for food
上天会惩罚你的
God will punish you.
原振侠就快来杀你了
Yuan Chan is coming to kill you
我现在就是想等他们来
I'm waiting for them now.
我们已经来了
We are here!
我都说过他会来的
I told you he would come
老祖宗
Old Ancestor!
阿古拉，你作恶多端，多行不义
Aquala, you did many atrocties
今天要你作法自毙
I'll make you pay for them now.
老祖宗
Old Ancestor!
快走
Let's go!
小心
Watch out!
彩虹
Rainbow!
黑龙
Black Dragon!
走开呀
Stay aside!
放鬼仔
Let loose the Little Ghost!
那颗舍利子呢？
Where's the grain?
在这儿
It's here.
糟了，已经过时了
Damn, it's over the time.
那芭珠不是不能恢复原来的样子了
Betsy can't restore her original looks then
黑龙，如果我一辈子都是这个样子
Dragon, would you love me still
还爱不爱我？
if I look like this all my life?
大巫师已经死了 我们的族人从此得到新生
The sorcerer is dead Our tribes can lead a new life from now on.
我可以帮他们生活得好一点
I can help them live better.
那……那不是很可惜？
Isn't that a pity?
一个人真正的美不是在她的脸上
Beauty lies on one's heart.
而是在她心里面
not on one's face